https://www.seeintl.org/privacy/

Privacy Policy - SEE International
Navigation About SEEOverviewBlogBoard of DirectorsManagement TeamFinancialsMediaVideosA Mother’s WishA Dream of Sight – The Story of José RosasA Grandmother Sees AgainA Commitment to SightA Chance to See AgainSecond SightPublicationsStories From The FieldPressPress Room2015 United Nations Nelson Mandela PrizeEventsWhat We DoWhere We WorkInternational ProgramsInternational Programs OverviewGlobal Program PartnersSEE Docs & Medical VolunteersMedical Textbook DonationUS ProgramsSanta Barbara Vision Care ProgramCourses & TrainingsConditions & Diseases We TreatCataractsChildhood Blindness in Developing CountriesCorneal BlindnessDiabetic RetinopathyGlaucomaStrabismusStories From The FieldVolunteerSEE Docs & Medical VolunteersOverviewRequirementsAnnual SEE Doc DuesCourses & TrainingsHumanitarian Travel ResourcesGeneral VolunteersWhy Volunteer?Get InvolvedContact UsSpeakers BureauEmployment & InternshipsJoin Our Mailing ListContact UsDonateDonate OnlineCorporate & Foundation SearchAbout SEEOverviewBlogBoard of DirectorsManagement TeamFinancialsMediaVideosA Mother’s WishA Dream of Sight – The Story of José RosasA Grandmother Sees AgainA Commitment to SightA Chance to See AgainSecond SightPublicationsStories From The FieldPressPress Room2015 United Nations Nelson Mandela PrizeEventsWhat We DoWhere We WorkInternational ProgramsInternational Programs OverviewGlobal Program PartnersSEE Docs & Medical VolunteersMedical Textbook DonationUS ProgramsSanta Barbara Vision Care ProgramCourses & TrainingsConditions & Diseases We TreatCataractsChildhood Blindness in Developing CountriesCorneal BlindnessDiabetic RetinopathyGlaucomaStrabismusStories From The FieldVolunteerSEE Docs & Medical VolunteersOverviewRequirementsAnnual SEE Doc DuesCourses & TrainingsHumanitarian Travel ResourcesGeneral VolunteersWhy Volunteer?Get InvolvedContact UsSpeakers BureauEmployment & InternshipsJoin Our Mailing ListContact UsDonateDonate OnlineCorporate & Foundation SearchPrivacy PolicyPrivacy PolicyEffective Date: May 25, 2018SEE International holds protecting the privacy of our donors, website visitors, and other individuals, as a top priority. This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit or make a purchase from our website. The following applies when you donate to our organization, either online or otherwise, or otherwise share your personal information with SEE. All individuals visiting our website are understood to accept this Privacy Policy. Hard copies are available upon request.For any questions or concerns about how collected data is used, or how SEE protects users’ privacy, please email us at info@seeintl.org. We may also be reached at our office, located at 175 Cremona Drive, Suite 100, Santa Barbara, CA 93117.Normal BrowsingWhen accessing our website, SEE will only collect personally identifying information from you if you choose to provide such information to us. You do not need to tell us who you are, or reveal any information about yourself.We collect browsing information from two sources:1 – standard server logs collect information such as the IP (Internet Protocol) address, domain name, browser type, and operating system, as well as mobile-related information if you access our website using your mobile device.2 – information such as the site that referred you to us, the files you downloaded, the pages you visited, and the dates/times of those visits. This is to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site.Additionally, if you have come into the site from one of our newsletters or from a site that has requested a link to us, we will ask your browser to accept a cookie that carries a general marketing source code with you as you browse through the site, in order to help us match referring sites to donations made. This cookie does not capture or hold any personally identifying information about you, and is deleted when you end your session by leaving our site or closing your browser.Donor InformationSEE requests certain personally identifiable information from its donors, including the donor’s name, address, telephone number, email address, and credit card information. We use this information to process your donation, provide receipts, and contact you regarding your gift, if necessary. With your consent, SEE will also use your information to keep you updated about our work, track website analytics, personalize our online advertising campaigns, and improve our online content.If you make a donation in honor of someone else, SEE may collect the name and address of the honoree in order to notify them of any related donation or purchase order. When you provide us with personal information about your contacts, we will only use this information for the specific reason for which it is provided.We may receive information about you from other sources. By using publicly available databases or third parties from whom we have purchased data, we may update and analyze our records, profile users, and provide services that may be of interest to you.Examples include the following:Address information about you from the U.S. Postal Service, to verify your address so we can properly send you a gift receipt, and to prevent fraud.Purchased marketing data about our supporters, combined with information we already have, to customize communications and advertising.If you would like a copy of your information or want it removed from our database, please email us at info@seeintl.org, or call us at (805) 963-3303.Sharing with Third PartiesSEE does not sell, exchange, or share its mailing lists.SEE utilizes companies to host our donor database, send print and online communications, analyze data, and process donations and credit card payments. These companies are required to keep such information confidential, and may use this information only as necessary to provide these services to us. SEE may retain your information for as long as your account is active, or as needed to provide you services, comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce agreements. To have your contact information removed from our systems, email us at info@seeintl.org, or call us at (805) 963-3303. Other InformationSEE collects and stores personally identifiable information (such as your name, postal address, and email address) that you decide to submit for purposes other than donating (such as receiving an email newsletter or further information on a particular topic). We will only use this information for the purposes for which you submitted it. In addition, we may use such information to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, keep you updated about our work, analyze website usage, and improve our website’s content, layout, and services. We do not share this information with any third parties except those that assist us with certain functions, as described above.EmploymentAny information that you submit while seeking employment or a volunteer position with SEE will be viewed only by SEE for human resources purposes, and to assess your qualifications as an employee or volunteer.Other DisclosuresPlease be advised that we may disclose your personal information to the government or to third parties pursuant to law enforcement inquiries, court orders, subpoenas and similar requests, or when we otherwise believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary or appropriate in connection with any activity that violates the law or may expose us to liability.SecurityWe promise to do our utmost to secure the personal information that you send us online. Any information that you transmit to us via online form travels by high-grade encryption using the https protocol. We also require the companies we work with to process your online donation payments use high-grade encryption and security protocols, and that all vendors processing check and credit card transactions received on our behalf meet all industry standards. The personal information that you provide is stored in a secure location and accessible only by designated employees trained in the proper handling of customer information. We employ industry standard techniques such as firewalls, encryption, and site monitoring to protect your personally identifiable information from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the organization. For additional information, please call us at (805) 963-3303, or email us at info@seeintl.org.Cookies and Tracking TechnologiesWhat They AreCookies are small data files placed on your device when you visit a website and store information about how you used it. Pixel tags are small snippets of code or tiny images embedded on websites and in email that help us learn about how you interact with our site and emails.Why We Use ThemSEE’s website uses cookies and similar technologies to help recognize you as a repeat visitor and improve the quality of our services. By gathering broad information on our user base, we can improve our website and the content we provide.We also use cookies for our internet advertising campaigns, so that third-party vendors, including Google, can show you advertising about SEE as you browse the internet. This includes showing you ads based on your browsing activities, interests, and geographic location, as well as retargeting. Retargeting is a marketing tool that identifies you as a previous visitor to the SEE website and targets you for specific outreach messages, encouraging you to revisit our website or consider donating. The cookies will only be used to obtain non-personal information (you will be anonymous).Our website includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policies of the companies providing them.Your OptionsYou can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. However, if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website.To learn more about how to enable, disable, or delete cookies from your web browser, please visit here. To control flash cookies, which may be used on certain websites from time to time, please go here.If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click here. Please note that you will continue to receive generic ads.To read more or opt out of receiving cookies from Google advertising, please visit the Google advertising opt-out page.To learn more about targeted advertising, these providers, or how you may opt out, please visit the DAA’s consumer choice page at http://www.aboutads.info/choices.To learn more about additional similar tracking technologies that may be used by third parties, and how to opt out of them, please visit the National Advertising Initiative’s website at http://www.networkadvertising.org.External LinksSEE’s site contains links to other sites. Unless we expressly state otherwise, SEE makes no representations whatsoever concerning the content of those sites. The fact that SEE has provided a link to a site is not an endorsement, authorization, sponsorship, or affiliation with respect to such site, its owners, or its providers. There are risks associated with using any information, software, or products found on the Internet, and SEE cautions you to make sure that you understand these risks before retrieving, using, relying upon, or purchasing anything via the Internet.Please be aware that SEE is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. Our Privacy Policy applies to all web pages under our domains, and not to any web pages not under our domains, regardless of any hyperlinks from a web page under our domains to a web page not under our domains.Note to Parents and ChildrenConsistent with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (“COPPA”), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without prior verifiable parental consent. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with such information without consent, we will use our best efforts to remove such information from our files. If you are a parent or guardian whose child under 13 has provided such information to us, contact us at (805) 963-3303, or at info@seeintl.org.Updating Your InformationUpon request, SEE International will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. We work to process and maintain accurately the information that you share with us. If you have donated to us and would like to access, correct, update, or delete your personal data or to adjust your mail preferences, you can do so by calling us at (805) 963-3303, or emailing us at info@seeintl.org.Opt-Out PreferenceYou may sign up to receive emails, newsletters, or other communications from us. If you would like to discontinue receiving this information, you may update your email preferences by using the “Unsubscribe” link found in emails we send you, at your member profile on our website, by calling us at (805) 963-3303, or by emailing us at info@seeintl.org.Changes to this Privacy PolicyWe may, from time to time, make changes to our Privacy Policy, based on your comments and our need to reflect accurately our data collection and disclosure practices. If we make any material changes in the way we use your personal information, we will notify you by posting a prominent announcement on our website. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our Privacy Policy.International Privacy LawsIf you are visiting our website from outside the United States, please be aware that you are sending information, including personal data, to the United States, where our servers are located. That information may be transferred within the United States or back out of the United States to other countries outside your country of residence, depending on the type of information and how it is stored by us. These countries including the United States may not necessarily have data protection laws as comprehensive or protective as those in the country of your residence. However, our collection storage and use of your personal data will at all times continue to be governed by this privacy policy.Governing LawYou agree that your use of this Privacy Policy and any disputes relating thereto shall be governed in all respects by the laws of the State of California. Any dispute relating to this Privacy Policy shall be resolved solely in the state or federal courts located in California.This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 24, 2018. How You Can HelpDonate Events Fundraise Job Opportunities VolunteerResourcesFinancials Press Room Privacy Policy SEE Docs/Medical VolunteersSEE International175 Cremona Drive, Suite 100 Santa Barbara, CA 93117 USA 877-937-3133 | 805-963-3303 info@seeintl.orgJoin Our Mailing List SEE IS A 501(c)3 NONPROFIT ORGANIZATION WITH TAX-ID # 31-1682275Sight = Freedom Type and Press “enter” to Search
We use cookies to understand how you use our site and improve your experience. This includes providing customized content and advertising. By continuing to use this site, or by clicking "I Agree", you agree to our use of cookies. Please review our Privacy Policy for more information.I AgreeRead More
